<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Open Force Field Initiative</title>
    <link>//openforcefield.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Open Force Field Initiative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//openforcefield.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan 2019 Open Force Field Consortium Workshop</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</guid>
      <description>We hosted the first Open Force Field Consortium Workshop in La Jolla, CA on January 7-8, 2019. The meeting was open to Consortium members and collaborators, and parts of the meeting were recorded for posting online. In addition, slides discussing current Consortium research and future plans are given below.
Details at a glance  Date: January 7-8, 2018 Location: Jacobs Medical Center, UC San Diego, La Jolla, CA, Rooms 2 and 3 Local contact: Mike Gilson &amp;lt;mgilson@ucsd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar on the SMIRNOFF format and learned chemical perception Oct. 10</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</guid>
      <description>Check out a webinar on the Initiative this Oct. 10 from BioExcel! MolSSI fellow Caitlin Bannan will talk about the Initiative&amp;rsquo;s overall goals and her work on learned chemical perception. Register through BioExcel, or if you can&amp;rsquo;t make it, video should be available afterwards.
Bannan&amp;rsquo;s Abstract: The Open Force Field Initiative is developing a machinery to automatically parameterize molecular mechanics force fields. An important part of this process will be automating chemical perception — the way force field parameters are assigned to a molecule based on chemical environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Open Force Field Consortium</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</guid>
      <description>We’re excited to announce the launch of the Open Force Field Consortium, an academic-industry collaboration designed to improve small molecule force fields used to guide pharmaceutical drug discovery. The Open Force Field Initiative is what we are calling our overall research effort, whereas the Open Force Field Consortium refers specifically to the academic-industry collaboration.
Modeling tools based on force fields assist development of therapies for diseases such as cancer and neurodegenerative disease throughout academia and industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for open source cheminformatics toolkits is coming!</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve been hard at work with a large-scale infrastructure overhaul of our main openforcefield toolkit following the Open Force Field Toolkit 0.1.0 prerelease, which provided an initial reference implementation of the SMIRNOFF 0.1 specification for direct chemical perception. Many thanks to all the users who provided helpful feedback in how we could improve overall usability!
While we expect the updated toolkit to be released very soon, we wanted to provide a summary of the coming changes to give you an idea of what we&#39;ve been up to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Open Force Field Initiative</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</guid>
      <description>Molecular modeling is widely used in diverse pharmaceutical discovery applications, but its utility and predictive power is limited by the accuracy of the underlying molecular mechanics force field used to compute the energetics of biomolecular systems. The Open Force Field Initiative is an open effort to build iteratively more accurate force fields to improve predictive design, along with the necessary infrastructure to make these force fields easier to build and use, and to provide a modern platform for powering force field science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>