<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>force field on OpenFF</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/tags/force-field/</link><description>Recent content in force field on OpenFF</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openforcefield.org/tags/force-field/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Science</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/open-science-2022-12-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/open-science-2022-12-19/</guid><description>Science plays a crucial role in shaping our future and increasing knowledge is key to this progress. This is why initiatives like the Open Force Field, which aim to turn cutting-edge scientific research into valuable technology, need ongoing support. By providing long-term support to these initiatives, we can ensure that they can continue to develop and deliver comprehensive solutions that are accessible to all. It is important to recognize that the success of initiatives like the Open Force Field relies on ongoing interest and support.</description></item><item><title>Training force field parameters to Host-Guest binding</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/fitting_gbsa_parameters-openff-2022-08-29/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/fitting_gbsa_parameters-openff-2022-08-29/</guid><description>Would you like to train your force field to fit binding data? Most force fields are tuned to reproduce liquid state properties. Setting up simulations to perform the binding calculations and optimizing specific force field parameters may be laborious work. However, the Open Force Field infrastructure provides the tools to achieve this in an automated way. In this blog post, I will show an example of tuning GBSA parameters to host-guest binding data using Open Force Field.</description></item><item><title>Open Source, Enterprise-level Data Pipeline</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/dataset_generation-openff-2022-06-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/dataset_generation-openff-2022-06-13/</guid><description>In this blogpost I would like to introduce you to our molecular dataset generation workflow. At Open Force Field, we generate a lot of Quantum Mechanics (QM) data as well as Molecular Mechanics (MM) data, predominantly for drug-like small molecules. A few data oriented tasks include:
training the valence parameters in the force field benchmarking the force field building bespoke parameters based on fragment torsions building machine learning models to predict charges building machine learned potentials and many more analyses to answer scientific questions related to virtual sites, polarizability, etc.</description></item><item><title>BespokeFit release</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bespokefit-update-2022-05-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bespokefit-update-2022-05-12/</guid><description>We are very pleased to officially announce the release of 🎉openff-bespokefit🎉 for public use. The OpenFF BespokeFit framework aims to offer a completely automated workflow for creating bespoke, highly accurate, torsion parameters in the OpenFF SMIRNOFF format. Following our very early alpha preview late last year we have been hard at work to improve the experience that users can expect with BespokeFit, concentrating on a few key aspects:
Reliability: BespokeFit should be able to reliably derive bespoke parameters for a wide range of drug-like molecules and so we have reworked our reference data generation to work with the fantastic QCEngine to offer a reliable and reproducible fitting experience.</description></item><item><title>Benchmark: Collaborative assessment of molecular geometries and energies from the OpenFF</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/benchmarking-openff-2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/benchmarking-openff-2022-04-15/</guid><description>The Open Force Field (OpenFF) Initiative focuses to build, optimize and assess a general force field (FF) using an automated and reproducible procedure, with all software, data, and workflows made freely available. Recently, the second generation of small molecule force field “Sage” (OpenFF 2.y.z) was released, featuring a retrained Lennard-Jones parameters in addition to continued improvements to the valence parameters. In this report, academic and industrial partners of the OpenFF Initiative worked together to assess the performance of recent OpenFF releases and other small molecule FFs against reference quantum mechanical (QM) calculations at the B3LYP-D3BJ/DZVP level of theory.</description></item><item><title>How to train your force field 2: Bespoke fit</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bespokefit-update-2021-10-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bespokefit-update-2021-10-20/</guid><description>General transferable force fields, such as Parsley or Sage, allow us to rapidly parameterize small molecules covering vast amounts of chemical space for use in molecular dynamics simulations. However, with every force field comes the inherent assumption that parameters fit to a set of representative molecules in a training set are transferable to any new molecules with similar chemistry. Despite potential accuracy problems caused by poor transferability or discrete atom types the use of force fields in fields like drug discovery has been a massive success.</description></item><item><title>Surrogate-enabled Bayesian sampling of force field parameters</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bayesian-surrogate-modeling-2021-09-03/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/bayesian-surrogate-modeling-2021-09-03/</guid><description>In the Open Force Field Initiative, we are always looking for novel ways to advance force field parameterization. Working on the parameterization of Lennard-Jones models, one strategy I am exploring is using Bayesian inference to explore parameter landscapes with respect to physical properties. This is a lot to parse in one sentence, so let&amp;rsquo;s break it down!
Lennard-Jones parameterization relies on physical properties Since the earliest days of force field science, LJ parameters have been fitted against physical property datasets ( typically liquid densities and heats of vaporization).</description></item><item><title>Searching chemical space</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/searching-chemical-space-2021-07-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/searching-chemical-space-2021-07-26/</guid><description>The basis of SMIRNOFF is the use of SMIRKS (or SMARTS) patterns to define parameters. This has a lot of benefits and makes parameter design and force field fitting a unique experience. Because of this uniqueness I have found a need to use SMARTS in a way that just hasn&amp;rsquo;t been needed until now. SMARTS are normally applied to a SMILES pattern which makes SMARTS a type of substructure query on a molecule.</description></item><item><title>How to train your force field</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/ff-training-example-2021-07-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/ff-training-example-2021-07-01/</guid><description>Within Open Force Field (as the name might suggest) a lot of time and effort is spent exploring exactly how should force fields be trained - what data should be fit to? how should that data influence the optimization e.g. L1, L2? what classical functional forms should be used for the force field interactions? or should everything just be machine learned a la ANI and friends.
A big part of this process is automation.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Lessons-learned</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/infrastructure-update-2021-05-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/infrastructure-update-2021-05-19/</guid><description>It’s been more than a year since our last blog post, far longer than we could reasonably blame on lockdowns. This post will be an update after a year of software development and operational lessons-learned. In some ways this post may be interesting for an actual software person to read, since getting myself to this point required so many years of biology, chemistry, physics, and CS, that I never formally learned software engineering or project management, yet those have gradually become my primary roles in the organization.</description></item><item><title>Announcing two new releases!</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/new-releases-oct2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/new-releases-oct2020/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce TWO releases are now available!
Force fields OpenFF-1.3.0, a minor update to Parsley that improves performance on amide geometries. Detailed release notes are available here.
OpenFF Toolkit The Open Force Field Toolkit version 0.8.0. This release adds our largest feature yet, SMARTS-based creation of VirtualSites (also known as off-center charges), as well as functionality to handle bond parameter interpolation based on partial bond orders. Detailed release notes are available at here.</description></item><item><title>Version 1.1.0 "Parsley" Update</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/v1.1.0-parsley-update-2020-03-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/v1.1.0-parsley-update-2020-03-03/</guid><description>Description We are pleased to announce the release of our first &amp;ldquo;Parsley&amp;rdquo; update. Version 1.1.0 &amp;ldquo;Parsley&amp;rdquo; is a minor release that includes some adjustments in force field: (1) Addition of three new bond and angle terms, a22a, b14a and b36a; (2) Modification of periodicity for N-N rotations; (3) Addition of missing improper torsions (i2a, i3a, i3b, i5a) with the associated torsions (t51a,t51b, t51c); and (4) Removal of redundant periodicity in t19.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Andreas Krämer: Automated Optimization Approaches for the CHARMM Lipid Force Field (Dec 17, 2019)</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-kraemer-dec2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-kraemer-dec2019/</guid><description>Andreas Krämer (NIH) will give a talk about development of an automated optimization approach to improve the CHARMM36 lipid force field using pair-specific LJ parameters. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Dec 17 at 2 pm (ET), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** The [CHARMM36 (C36) lipid force field](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2922408/) is well-validated for many properties of monolayers and bilayers and has been cited in over 2000 studies of membrane simulations.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Falk Hoffmann: Using NMR relaxation data to improve the dynamics of methyl groups in AMBER and CHARMM force fields (Sep 20, 2019)</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-hoffman-sep2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-hoffman-sep2019/</guid><description>Falk Hoffmann from Lars Schaefer&amp;rsquo;s group at Ruhr University Bochum, will present his work on improving torsional barriers associated with methyl group rotations in amino acid side-chains in AMBER and CHARMM force fields by using NMR relaxation rates. This study is available as a preprint on ChemrXiv. Join this seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 20 at 11 am (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.</description></item><item><title>Webinar by Chuan Tian: ff19SB - Amino acid specific protein backbone parameters trained against quantum mechanics energies in solution (Sep 12, 2019)</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-tian-sep2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-tian-sep2019/</guid><description>Chuan Tian from the Simmerling lab will visit the Chodera lab at MSKCC and give a talk about the latest Amber force field - ff19SB. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 12 at 1 pm (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations have become increasingly popular in studying the motions and functions of biomolecules. The accuracy of the simulation, however, is highly determined by the classical force field (FF), a set of functions with adjustable parameters to compute the potential energy from atomic positions.</description></item><item><title>Release-1 update (Aug 15, 2019)</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</guid><description>Chemical coverage C. Bayly suggested broadly dividing parameters into two categories: 1) chemistry being covered in the first optimization run; 2) everything else. The latter category should also include information about all molecules that were cleaned out from databases used in the first optimization sprint, which was focused on improvement of a selected (sub)set of parameters. This information (data) can be used in the later stages of the force field optimization when chemical coverage will be expanded.</description></item><item><title>Release-1 update (Jul 16, 2019)</title><link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</guid><description>Types We will use the same typing tree as smirnoff99Frosst (with some minor adjustments to specific bugs or other problems), but optimize the differentiable parameters in (a subset of) torsion, valence, and Lennard-Jones parameters.
Parameterization We will aim to refit (a subset of) torsions, valence terms, and Lennard-Jones parameters, depending on what is ready in time. In practice, we have decoupled efforts to fit all three that should be straightforward to couple together in our final optimization stage.</description></item></channel></rss>