<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Open Force Field Initiative</title>
    <link>//openforcefield.org/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Open Force Field Initiative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//openforcefield.org/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Update</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2019-01-22-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2019-01-22-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Participants Caitlin Bannan (Mobley group), Simon Boothroyd (Chodera group), John Chodera (MSKCC), Hyesu Jang (Wang group), Victoria Lim (Mobley group), Jessica Maat (Mobley group), Owen Madin (Shirts group), David Mobley (UC Irvine), Levi Naden (MolSSI), Jessica Nash (MolSSI), Yudong Qiu (Wang group), Andrea Rizzi (Chodera group), Michael Schauperl (Gilson group), David Slochower (Gilson group), Daniel Smith (MolSSI), Chaya Stern (Chodera group), Jeff Wagner (OpenFF), Lee-Ping Wang (UC Davis)
Glossary MolSSI Cookiecutter: The MolSSI project cookiecutter for compuational and molecular sciences projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torsion subgroup update</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-16-torsions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-16-torsions/</guid>
      <description>Participants John Chodera (MSKCC), Jessica Maat (Mobley group), David Mobley (UC Irvine), Levi Naden (MolSSI), Jessica Nash (MolSSI), Yudong Qiu (Wang group), Daniel Smith (MolSSI), Chaya Stern (Chodera group), Jeff Wagner (OpenFF), Lee-Ping Wang (UC Davis)
Glossary geomeTRIC: Geometry optimization software package, Wang lab
fragmenter: Fragment molecules for QM torsion scans, Chodera lab. Provides input to torsiondrive and QCFractal.
torsiondrive: Manages geometry optimization calculations for torsion scan, Wang lab. Uses geomeTRIC to carry out optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Open Force Field Science Updates</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-11-chodera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-11-chodera/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to introduce Open Force Field Science Updates, a lightweight science blog series in which researchers working with the Open Force Field Initiative will post about their research and engineering directions and scientific progress on various aspects of the Initiative. To start with, researchers will post roughly once every two weeks around the time of subgroup project meetings, with posts tagged by the subgroup activity. These posts will often include figures, like these from our ThermoML Archive benchmark paper:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>