<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>property selection on OpenFF</title>
    <link>https://openforcefield.org/tags/property-selection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in property selection on OpenFF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openforcefield.org/tags/property-selection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Property Estimator Meeting Summary (Jul 11, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertyestimator-meeting-2019-07-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertyestimator-meeting-2019-07-11/</guid>
      <description>Dataset sources
NIST update: Data that was collected and curated in an automated process by NIST could be released as an open dataset, but not the manually curated uncertainties, which is the step that follows automated curation. Additional problem may arise from the fact that data from before 10 years ago simply isn’t present in ThermoML. Until the situation is clear from the legal perspective, it has been decided to move forward using the data from an older release of ThermoML which contained author-assigned uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Estimator Meeting Summary (Jun 27, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertyestimator-meeting-2019-06-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertyestimator-meeting-2019-06-27/</guid>
      <description>Property selection: Discussion about which properties and the exact amount of data to be requested from NIST continues. One of the challenges is to find the right balance between the current and future parameterization needs, which includes making decisions about specific properties to be used for the first optimization sprint and specific chemistry that will be covered in this sprint (and maybe in the next one). For the latter, finding a set of molecules (SMILES) that exercise all SMIRNOFF parameters is desirable and J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Jan 31, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Property selection: L.-P. Wang suggested using surface tension for parameter fitting, which isn’t a traditional property used in force field parameterization. A discussion ensued about the merits of using surface tension as one of the target properties, and whether precedents in literature exists. L.-P. Wang described some previous work looking at the simulations of a slab of liquid showing moderate agreement with experiment, and highlighted that, according to the study, the results are relatively consistent as long as the film has no holes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
