<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PropertyCalculator on OpenFF</title>
    <link>https://openforcefield.org/tags/propertycalculator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PropertyCalculator on OpenFF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openforcefield.org/tags/propertycalculator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (October 17, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-10-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-10-17/</guid>
      <description>This meeting was the first dedicated Property Estimator call after several weeks of focus on producing and benchmarking release-1 (Parsley / openff-1.0.0.offxml). It focused on deciding future directions toward publication, infrastructure development, and lining up for the next FF release.
 Once Simon Boothroyd begins work in Colorado, Simon and Owen will present a proposed Property Estimator paper outline to the consortium. This will involve choosing which of several existing questions to address, including:  The extent to which our current functional form introduces errors in polyhalogenated compounds, due to an inability to model sigma holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-05-23-madin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-05-23-madin/</guid>
      <description>Today on the #propertycalculator call, we discussed working with NIST and their ThermoML property database to obtain a suitable dataset for parameterizing and benchmarking small molecules.
 The Open Force Field Initiative is working with NIST in order to make a subset of ThermoML (and associated NIST uncertainties, which are essential for planned Bayesian analysis) publically available. We defined preliminary SQL queries for the chemistries, conditions, and properties that OpenFF is interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (May 02, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-05-02/</guid>
      <description>Benchmarking protein-ligand free energy: A set of suitable protein-ligand structures that will be used for the initial force field fitting/benchmarking during Year 1 (likely in September) needs to be selected. J. Chodera suggested the D3R Grand Challenge set as a starting point, but it needs to be filtered to remove any structures that might make benchmarking more complicated. For example, the structures with binding sites containing metals or histidines, titratable ligands that might change protonation states upon binding, buried sites, protein dimers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Apr 18, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-04-18/</guid>
      <description>The majority of this meeting focused on how to store and present the “best practices” for property calculation. A few actionable conclusions came from this meeting:
 We might call them “selected practices” instead of “best practices”; 8 For the foreseeable future, these documents will live in the openforcefield/propertyestimator repo, alongside the actual code. Each property will have a page with both links to the technical (API) details and theoretical discussion; The Shirts lab will work on example code for reweighting host-guest calculations; S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Mar 21, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-03-21/</guid>
      <description>Datasets: S. Boothroyd reported that NIST uncertainty values disappeared after a reformat of the stored data. He has also raised an issue with target uncertainties in the simulations because ThermoML has very low uncertainties and simulations might have to be significantly extended to reach an order of magnitude smaller values. There are several potential ways to address this problem, including running simulations to an absolute uncertainty and analyzing existing entries in ThermoML to understand the range of uncertainties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Feb 21, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-02-21/</guid>
      <description>This call focused on RJMC preliminary results for surrogate models (O. Madin, R. Messerly) and implicit solvation (J. Fass).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Feb 07, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Host-guest calculator: The main topic of discussion was the API design for host-guest calculations. There is a number of decisions that have to be made with respect to input/output requirements, handling different rates of convergence between different systems, how to define and reach targeted uncertainties etc. The current plan envisages the following solutions:
 PropertyCalculator would run a simulation in a loop and pause at given intervals to check for convergence and return value, associated uncertainties and location of data files, which is necessary for reweighting, but it will be implemented later on; Initial analysis implementation will involve independent simulations instead of an ensemble analysis to meet a target uncertainty (per-window uncertainty); Returning gradients will be an optional argument, probably in the second generation of fitting with reweighting; As a job input, the estimator should receive a ForceField object and a description of the measured chemical mixture and conditions that it will estimate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Jan 31, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Property selection: L.-P. Wang suggested using surface tension for parameter fitting, which isn’t a traditional property used in force field parameterization. A discussion ensued about the merits of using surface tension as one of the target properties, and whether precedents in literature exists. L.-P. Wang described some previous work looking at the simulations of a slab of liquid showing moderate agreement with experiment, and highlighted that, according to the study, the results are relatively consistent as long as the film has no holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Jan 24, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2019-01-24/</guid>
      <description>API: This meeting focused on API design aspects of PropertyCalculator, including how to tackle situations in which multiple properties with different convergence rates are computed from the same simulation. These properties could be reported asynchronously, as they are being computed, or they could only be returned upon successful completion of all property calculations. It has been decided to build the API with a possibility to allow asynchronous reporting in the future, although this feature is not expected to be implemented in the near-term future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Dec 13, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-12-13/</guid>
      <description>A number of decisions will have to be made about the PropertyCalculator framework and it has been decided to create two best practice documents for the purpose of property estimation within the OpenFF effort:
 The best practice document for calculating properties in general (from a theoretical standpoint); A specific document which contains best practices for computing properties using OFF tools and force fields, i.e. a specific implementation of the practices described in the document 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Nov 29, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-11-29/</guid>
      <description>Property Calculator: This call focused on the Property Calculator Framework and outlining some basic design concepts and use cases. The shortest term application is benchmarking for force field parameters. Certain design aspects need further discussion, but the initial rough kernel for setting up simulations at chosen properties/parameters should contain simplistic building blocks: smiles → smirnoff parameters → energy minimization → simulation. MBAR/surrogate model levels are yet to be defined, including model specification options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Calculator Meeting Summary (Oct 11, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/propertycalculator-meeting-2018-10-11/</guid>
      <description>Surrogate models/RJMC: O. Madin and R. Messerly presented reversible-jump Monte Carlo (RJMC) performance study focused on L-J parameter space and compared it with numerical integration of probability regions in an analytical surrogate model. These preliminary results show that the two methods are in qualitative agreement, but quantitative discrepancies are suspected to arise due to grid spacing in numerical integration or scaling maps. The main goal of this exercise was to validate RJMC sampling coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
