<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>parameters on OpenFF</title>
    <link>https://openforcefield.org/tags/parameters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in parameters on OpenFF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openforcefield.org/tags/parameters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Version 1.1.0 &#34;Parsley&#34; Update (March 03, 2020)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/v1.1.0-parsley-update-2020-03-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/v1.1.0-parsley-update-2020-03-03/</guid>
      <description>Description We are pleased to announce the release of our first &amp;ldquo;Parsley&amp;rdquo; update. Version 1.1.0 &amp;ldquo;Parsley&amp;rdquo; is a minor release that includes some adjustments in force field: (1) Addition of three new bond and angle terms, a22a, b14a and b36a; (2) Modification of periodicity for N-N rotations; (3) Addition of missing improper torsions (i2a, i3a, i3b, i5a) with the associated torsions (t51a,t51b, t51c); and (4) Removal of redundant periodicity in t19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar by Chuan Tian: ff19SB - Amino acid specific protein backbone parameters trained against quantum mechanics energies in solution (Sep 12, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-tian-sep2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/general/webinar-tian-sep2019/</guid>
      <description>Chuan Tian from the Simmerling lab will visit the Chodera lab at MSKCC and give a talk about the latest Amber force field - ff19SB. Join the seminar via Zoom in real time on Sep 12 at 1 pm (EDT), or watch it later on our YouTube channel.
**Abstract:** Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations have become increasingly popular in studying the motions and functions of biomolecules. The accuracy of the simulation, however, is highly determined by the classical force field (FF), a set of functions with adjustable parameters to compute the potential energy from atomic positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-1 update (Aug 15, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</guid>
      <description>Chemical coverage C. Bayly suggested broadly dividing parameters into two categories: 1) chemistry being covered in the first optimization run; 2) everything else. The latter category should also include information about all molecules that were cleaned out from databases used in the first optimization sprint, which was focused on improvement of a selected (sub)set of parameters. This information (data) can be used in the later stages of the force field optimization when chemical coverage will be expanded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-1 update (Jul 16, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</guid>
      <description>Types We will use the same typing tree as smirnoff99Frosst (with some minor adjustments to specific bugs or other problems), but optimize the differentiable parameters in (a subset of) torsion, valence, and Lennard-Jones parameters.
Parameterization We will aim to refit (a subset of) torsions, valence terms, and Lennard-Jones parameters, depending on what is ready in time. In practice, we have decoupled efforts to fit all three that should be straightforward to couple together in our final optimization stage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
