<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Force Field Initiative</title>
    <link>//openforcefield.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Open Force Field Initiative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//openforcefield.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>January 23, 2019 Advisory Board Meeting</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-23-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-23-minutes/</guid>
      <description>The Open Force Field Consortium Advisory Board met on 23 Jan 2019. The minutes are summarized as follows:
Open Forcefield Advisory Board Meeting Minutes – January 23, 2019  RDKit Integration  Key infrastructure seems to be working Currently implementing testing to make sure energies/parameters are same between RDKit and OpenEye toolkit backends Documentation being worked on Limited to SDF file format initially RDKit support being added initially for OpenFF toolkit, not for other packages being used internally for parameter development Bespoke torsion parameterization tool will be able to use RDKit or other wholly open-source backend  Workflows  Workflow documentation / example requests should be posted to #documentation Slack channel Some suggested workflows from agenda and discussion: Parameterization of protein-ligand system using SMIRNOFF Conformer energy evaluation Minimization of multiple ligands from SDF file (is this with protein, without, both?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Update</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2019-01-22-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2019-01-22-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Participants Caitlin Bannan (Mobley group), Simon Boothroyd (Chodera group), John Chodera (MSKCC), Hyesu Jang (Wang group), Victoria Lim (Mobley group), Jessica Maat (Mobley group), Owen Madin (Shirts group), David Mobley (UC Irvine), Levi Naden (MolSSI), Jessica Nash (MolSSI), Yudong Qiu (Wang group), Andrea Rizzi (Chodera group), Michael Schauperl (Gilson group), David Slochower (Gilson group), Daniel Smith (MolSSI), Chaya Stern (Chodera group), Jeff Wagner (OpenFF), Lee-Ping Wang (UC Davis)
Glossary MolSSI Cookiecutter: The MolSSI project cookiecutter for compuational and molecular sciences projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 7-8, 2019 Consortium Workshop</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-07-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2019-01-07-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Minutes: Attending: All PIs and software scientists; most industry partners, postdocs, and students (including via Zoom); academic and industry community members
Visit the agenda page for more details of the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torsion subgroup update</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-16-torsions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-16-torsions/</guid>
      <description>Participants John Chodera (MSKCC), Jessica Maat (Mobley group), David Mobley (UC Irvine), Levi Naden (MolSSI), Jessica Nash (MolSSI), Yudong Qiu (Wang group), Daniel Smith (MolSSI), Chaya Stern (Chodera group), Jeff Wagner (OpenFF), Lee-Ping Wang (UC Davis)
Glossary geomeTRIC: Geometry optimization software package, Wang lab
fragmenter: Fragment molecules for QM torsion scans, Chodera lab. Provides input to torsiondrive and QCFractal.
torsiondrive: Manages geometry optimization calculations for torsion scan, Wang lab. Uses geomeTRIC to carry out optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Open Force Field Science Updates</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-11-chodera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/science/updates/2018-10-11-chodera/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to introduce Open Force Field Science Updates, a lightweight science blog series in which researchers working with the Open Force Field Initiative will post about their research and engineering directions and scientific progress on various aspects of the Initiative. To start with, researchers will post roughly once every two weeks around the time of subgroup project meetings, with posts tagged by the subgroup activity. These posts will often include figures, like these from our ThermoML Archive benchmark paper:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 11, 2018 Governing Board Meeting</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-11-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-11-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Agenda:  October meeting draft agenda and start time January meeting location Maat hiring Slack Funding processing update/onboarding update Involvement with science meetings (subprojects) and project planning Discuss blog posts? Yes, just get sub-groups to do brief updates after meetings; better for keeping people up to date.  Minutes: Attending: All PIs except Shirts, and both industry members, Thomas Fox and Katharina Meier
Shared the detailed budget outline Google Doc and went over the personnel who would be involved and their distribution across different locations, $ amounts, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 29, 2018 Joint Governing/Advisory Board Meeting</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-29-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/consortium/minutes/2018-10-29-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Minutes: Attending: All PIs, both governing board members, and most advisory board members, via Zoom.
Short-term roadmap/minimum viable product: In general folks are supportive of current effort plans. However, there was consensus we need a tool for bespoke parameterization of molecules, especially internal molecules which might not be able to be disclosed to the larger effort, as part of our minimum viable product.
Funding/financials:  Currently we have eight partners on board (with openforcefield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan 2019 Open Force Field Consortium Workshop</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/jan-2019-meeting-agenda/</guid>
      <description>We hosted the first Open Force Field Consortium Workshop in La Jolla, CA on January 7-8, 2019. The meeting was open to Consortium members and collaborators, and parts of the meeting were recorded for posting online. In addition, slides discussing current Consortium research and future plans are given below.
Details at a glance  Date: January 7-8, 2018 Location: Jacobs Medical Center, UC San Diego, La Jolla, CA, Rooms 2 and 3 Local contact: Mike Gilson &amp;lt;mgilson@ucsd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar on the SMIRNOFF format and learned chemical perception Oct. 10</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/bioexcel_webinar/</guid>
      <description>Check out a webinar on the Initiative this Oct. 10 from BioExcel! MolSSI fellow Caitlin Bannan will talk about the Initiative&amp;rsquo;s overall goals and her work on learned chemical perception. Register through BioExcel, or if you can&amp;rsquo;t make it, video should be available afterwards.
Bannan&amp;rsquo;s Abstract: The Open Force Field Initiative is developing a machinery to automatically parameterize molecular mechanics force fields. An important part of this process will be automating chemical perception — the way force field parameters are assigned to a molecule based on chemical environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Open Force Field Consortium</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-consortium/</guid>
      <description>We’re excited to announce the launch of the Open Force Field Consortium, an academic-industry collaboration designed to improve small molecule force fields used to guide pharmaceutical drug discovery. The Open Force Field Initiative is what we are calling our overall research effort, whereas the Open Force Field Consortium refers specifically to the academic-industry collaboration.
Modeling tools based on force fields assist development of therapies for diseases such as cancer and neurodegenerative disease throughout academia and industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for open source cheminformatics toolkits is coming!</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/rdkit-support-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve been hard at work with a large-scale infrastructure overhaul of our main openforcefield toolkit following the Open Force Field Toolkit 0.1.0 prerelease, which provided an initial reference implementation of the SMIRNOFF 0.1 specification for direct chemical perception. Many thanks to all the users who provided helpful feedback in how we could improve overall usability!
While we expect the updated toolkit to be released very soon, we wanted to provide a summary of the coming changes to give you an idea of what we&#39;ve been up to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Open Force Field Initiative</title>
      <link>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//openforcefield.org/news/introducing-the-initiative/</guid>
      <description>Molecular modeling is widely used in diverse pharmaceutical discovery applications, but its utility and predictive power is limited by the accuracy of the underlying molecular mechanics force field used to compute the energetics of biomolecular systems. The Open Force Field Initiative is an open effort to build iteratively more accurate force fields to improve predictive design, along with the necessary infrastructure to make these force fields easier to build and use, and to provide a modern platform for powering force field science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>