<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>properties on OpenFF</title>
    <link>https://openforcefield.org/tags/properties/</link>
    <description>Recent content in properties on OpenFF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openforcefield.org/tags/properties/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Release-1 update (Aug 15, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/release-1-update-2019-08-20/</guid>
      <description>Chemical coverage C. Bayly suggested broadly dividing parameters into two categories: 1) chemistry being covered in the first optimization run; 2) everything else. The latter category should also include information about all molecules that were cleaned out from databases used in the first optimization sprint, which was focused on improvement of a selected (sub)set of parameters. This information (data) can be used in the later stages of the force field optimization when chemical coverage will be expanded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-1 update (Jul 16, 2019)</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-16-release-1/</guid>
      <description>Types We will use the same typing tree as smirnoff99Frosst (with some minor adjustments to specific bugs or other problems), but optimize the differentiable parameters in (a subset of) torsion, valence, and Lennard-Jones parameters.
Parameterization We will aim to refit (a subset of) torsions, valence terms, and Lennard-Jones parameters, depending on what is ready in time. In practice, we have decoupled efforts to fit all three that should be straightforward to couple together in our final optimization stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards New Fixed Charge Models</title>
      <link>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-05-charge-model-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openforcefield.org/community/news/science-updates/2019-07-05-charge-model-update/</guid>
      <description>The Open Force Field Initiative continues to explore new partial charge assignment models for both fast parameterization (to allow billion-compound sets to be rapidly parameterized for docking) and a more accurate &amp;ldquo;bespoke&amp;rdquo; parameterization pipeline for torsions and partial charges (intended for use with more accurate but more costly methods, such as free energy calculations).&amp;quot;
A new version of the Restrained Electrostatic Potential Method (RESP2): RESP2 aims to improve the electrostatic description via point charges, in comparison to the popular existing RESP (here referred to as “RESP1”) and AM1-BCC methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
